DAVID HASTIE

Personal Information

Phone: 07895340838 email: dh429@kent.ac.uk website: dhastie.space

An intuitive problem solver with a background in physics and

analysis. A driven team communicator looking for

opportunities to learn new skills and to engage new challenges.

EDUCATION

Profile

2015-2016 Master of Science in Physics (MSc)

THESIS SUBMITTED - AWAITING RESULT

University of Kent, Canterbury

 Research upon star formation using a theoretical Fortran model. Found correlations and significant points of interest in data using strong analytical techniques. Research made effective comparisons between observational and theoretical data.

2011-2015

Bachelor of Science in Physics with foundation year (BSc)

Upper Second Class Honours (67%)

University of Kent, Canterbury

Foundation Year: 71% 1st Year: 63%

Introductory Physics Lab - 62% Skills for Physicists (Lab) - 68%

Calculus - 94% Computing Skills - 60%

2nd Year: 66% 3rd Year: 67%

Atomic & Nuclear Numerical & Computational

Physics - 81% Methods - 70%

Quantum Physics - 58% Solid State Physics - 63%

- 3rd year lab project over an eight week period to create, code and test a three axis gimbal camera mount using an Arduino controller. Received 74% mark based upon the final report.
- Achieved 70% in a 3rd year group research project. Marks based on team presentation and dissertation components.

2008-2010

A levels

The Misbourne School, Buckinghamshire

Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry.

Personal Skills

 Computing proficiency gained from hobbies and previous work. Excellent Knowledge with MS office applications and LATEX.

Computing skills

 Fundamental Fortran and IDL programming knowledge gained from Masters research. Modules of Image Processing and Numerical Methods focused upon MATLAB techniques.

Problem Solving

- Attained through a 3rd year module 'Physics Problem Solving' which required initiative and logical thinking to solve a wide variety of physics based problems. Acheived - 76%.
- Masters research tested and applied data analysis techniques learned from other fields of research.
- Exceptional written and oral communications attained over many years of laboratory reports and modules with presentation and essay components.

Communication skills

- 3rd Year group project required team communication to ensure individuals skills were best utilised and the end product was concurrent.
- Independently learnt LATEX as to convey scientific research in a professional manner.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software Competent with MS office applications.

Fundamental knowledge of MATLAB.

Languages Compent with LATEX.

Fundamental skills in Fortran, IDL, Python and C++.

Systems Linux, OS X, Windows.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Self Employed 2014-Present

INDEPENDENT ONLINE RESELLER

- An independent role requiring discipline and dedication to source and acquire inventory for resale based upon simple business ideas.
- Developed an automated python programme that uses an API to track data for a large number of products. Hosted on a personal dedicated R-Pi Server.
- Implemented data analysis to measure profitability. An alert system is then used to inform the user of items that reach a threshold.

Pantry (Cafe) 2012-2015

Barista

- A fast paced position requiring team skills including clear verbal communication to accomplish tasks efficiently.
- Taught to intuitively fulfil roles as needs fluctuate.

PC World 2010-2011

Customer Service & Computer Repairs

- A team based role, providing experience in using multiple platforms of communication with colleagues, management and customers.
- Served as an introduction to a variety of computer skills including diagnostics and error checking.

Interests

Astro-Photography - Open Source Technology Custom Computers - Programming - Kick Boxing - Travelling